{
  "questions": [
    {
      "category": "Pretest",
      "question": "Which of the following are symptoms of hypoglycemia? ",
      "options": {
        "A": "(A) tachycardia and trembling",
        "B": "(B) bradycardia and diaphoresis",
        "C": "(C) anxiety and flushed, dry skin",
        "D": "(D) flushed, dry skin and tachycardia"
      },
      "correct_answer": "(A)",
      "explanation": "(A) When the blood glucose drops, sympathetic stimulation occurs. (Symptoms are masked for a patient who is receiving beta-adrenergic blocker drugs.) Flushed, dry skin is a sign of hyperglycemia."
    },
    {
      "category": "Pretest",
      "question": "Which of the following is TRUE for a patient who has had a right-sided stroke and develops increased intracranial pressure? ",
      "options": {
        "A": "(A) The pupils will change before the level of consciousness does, there will be right-sided\nparalysis, the eyes will be deviated to the left, and there will be a left pupil change.",
        "B": "(B) The pupils will change before the level of consciousness does, there will be left-sided",
        "C": "(C) The level of consciousness will change before there will be pupil changes, there\nparalysis, the eyes will be deviated to the right, and there will be a right pupil change.\nwill be right-sided paralysis, the eyes will be deviated to the left, and there will be\na left pupil change.",
        "D": "(D) The level of consciousness will change before there will be pupil changes, there will be left-sided paralysis, the eyes will be deviated to the right, and there will be\na right pupil change."
      },
      "correct_answer": "(D)",
      "explanation": "(D) Higher brain centers (cerebral cortex) are the first to be affected by increased intracranial  pressure. Therefore, the level of consciousness is the first sign (the one exception  to that rule is epidural hematoma). Pupil changes are ipsilateral (same side as the injury) due to compression of cranial nerve II against the transtentorial notch. Motor changes are contralateral (opposite side of the injury) due to motor fiber crossing in the brain stem."
    },
    {
      "category": "Pretest",
      "question": "A patient status-post head trauma has an ICP of 32 mmHg. Which of the following interventions is contraindicated for this patient? ",
      "options": {
        "A": "(A) Provide enteral feeding via a nasal tube.",
        "B": "(B) Elevate the head of bed 30-45 degrees.",
        "C": "(C) Maintain MAP 50-60 mmHg.",
        "D": "(D) Avoid hypotonic intravenous solutions."
      },
      "correct_answer": "(C)",
      "explanation": "(C) The patient has an elevated ICP. and the patient requires a MAP greater than 50-60 mmHg in order to maintain cerebral perfusion pressure and prevent brain ischemia. The remaining interventions listed in choices (A), (B), and (D) are indicated for a patient with an elevated ICP."
    },
    {
      "category": "Pretest",
      "question": "Which of the following is associated with mitral regurgitation? ",
      "options": {
        "A": "(A) systolic murmur, sinus bradycardia",
        "B": "(B) diastolic murmur, heart failure",
        "C": "(C) systolic murmur, inferior wall myocardial infarct",
        "D": "(D) diastolic murmur, complete heart block"
      },
      "correct_answer": "(C)",
      "explanation": "(C) Inferior wall MI may result in ischemia and dysfunction (regurgitation) of the mitral valve. The mitral valve is closed during systole (left ventricular ejection). A murmur  is produced when the mitral valve is not fully closed during systole."
    },
    {
      "category": "Pretest",
      "question": "A nurse knows that research supports a patient having unresrestricted access to his or her designated  support person (according to the patients wishes). However, the nurse's unit   restricts all patient visitors to set times. The nurse's best response would be to: ",
      "options": {
        "A": "(A) gather the facts and propose a policy change to the manager for the unit.",
        "B": "(B) tell patients/visitors that the unit's policy is outdated but there is nothing that\ncan be done about it.",
        "C": "(C) continue to follow the unit policy.",
        "D": "(D) complain to colleagues about the unit's outdated policy."
      },
      "correct_answer": "(A)",
      "explanation": "(A) The AACN Synergy Model supports patient advocacy. Unrestricted access to a designated  support person (according to the patient's wishes) is an evidence-based practice  that is included in the \"Family Presence: Visitation in the Adult ICU\" AACN Practice Alert. Choice (A) is an effective strategy for change."
    },
    {
      "category": "Pretest",
      "question": "Nitrate therapy is indicated for the treatment of unstable angina and acute heart failure because it: ",
      "options": {
        "A": "(A) decreases preload and increases myocardial O2 demand.",
        "B": "(B) increases preload and increases myocardial O2 demand.",
        "C": "(C) increases preload and decreases myocardial O2 demand.",
        "D": "(D) decreases preload and decreases myocardial O2 demand."
      },
      "correct_answer": "(D)",
      "explanation": "(D) Nitrates cause venodilation, which results in a decrease in venous return to the heart (left ventricular preload reduction). The decrease in preload decreases the work of the left ventricle and the myocardial oxygen demand."
    },
    {
      "category": "Pretest",
      "question": "A patient post-op CABG had a sudden decrease in mediastinal chest tube drainage with hypotension, narrowing pulse pressure, and respiratory variation on the arterial waveform (pulsus paradoxus). What other signs or symptoms would the nurse anticipate that this patient might exhibit? ",
      "options": {
        "A": "(A) muffled heart sounds",
        "B": "(B) decreased central venous pressure and increased pulmonary artery occlusion pressure",
        "C": "(C) flat neck veins",
        "D": "(D) ripping mid-scapular back pain"
      },
      "correct_answer": "(A)",
      "explanation": "(A) The patient history and signs and symptoms are indicative of cardiac tamponade, and muffled heart sounds are another sign. Cardiac tamponade is not characterized by a decrease in CVP and an increase in PAOP (choice (B)) or flat neck veins (choice (C), nor does it cause back pain (choice (D)."
    },
    {
      "category": "Pretest",
      "question": "A patient has just consented to a bedside chest tube insertion and requests that his wife be allowed to be present during the procedure. The nurse should: ",
      "options": {
        "A": "(A) explain to the patient that this is against infection control practices.",
        "B": "(B) tell the patient he will be able to see his wife as soon as the procedure is completed.",
        "C": "(C) tell the patient it would be too much for his wife to handle.",
        "D": "(D) prepare the wife for what to expect and allow her to be present."
      },
      "correct_answer": "(D)",
      "explanation": "(D) The AACN Synergy Model supports caring practices and family presence. An AACN Practice Alert indicates that family presence may improve the patient outcome."
    },
    {
      "category": "Pretest",
      "question": "ECG changes associated with ST-elevation myocardial infarction (STEMI) that affect the lateral wall would include changes in which of the following leads? ",
      "options": {
        "A": "(A) I, III, aVF",
        "B": "(B) V1, V2, V3",
        "C": "(C) V2, V3, V4",
        "D": "(D) V5, V6, I, aVL"
      },
      "correct_answer": "(D)",
      "explanation": "(D) V5 and V6 represent the lower lateral wall of the left ventricle, and I and aVL represent  the high lateral wall of the left ventricle, supplied by the left circumflex artery in most of the population."
    },
    {
      "category": "Pretest",
      "question": " Which of the following laboratory findings are most specifically indicative of disseminated intravascular coagulation (DIC) as the cause of bleeding? ",
      "options": {
        "A": "(A) elevated fibrin split products and D-dimer",
        "B": "(B) prolonged PT, PTT, and bleeding time",
        "C": "(C) decreased platelet count",
        "D": "(D) decreased hemoglobin and hematocrit"
      },
      "correct_answer": "(A)",
      "explanation": "(A) DIC is a clotting problem, with massive coagulation. As clots break down, fibrin split products are produced. Therefore, with DIC, FSPs will be high. In fact, this is the most specific test result for DIC. D-dimer is present due to the presence of clots. While not specific for DIC, it is a good rule-out test."
    },
    {
      "category": "Pretest",
      "question": " A 29-year-old female has been in the critical care unit for 2 days after a motor vehicle crash, and she has developed acute tubular necrosis (ATN). She was normotensive upon admission. What would be the most likely cause of her ATN? ",
      "options": {
        "A": "(A) hemorrhage",
        "B": "(B) rhabdomyolysis",
        "C": "(C) creatinine release",
        "D": "(D) cardiac dysrhythmias"
      },
      "correct_answer": "(B)",
      "explanation": "(B) The motor vehicle crash most likely resulted in a crush injury with destruction of skeletal muscle cells (rhabdomyolysis). This results in the release of massive amounts of creatine kinase (CK) that, in turn, may\"clog\" renal tubules and lead to acute tubular necrosis (ATN). Choice (A) is not correct, as there is no history of bleeding. Choice (C), creatinine release, is too vague, could be minor, and does not cause ATN. Cardiac dysrhythmias,  choice (D), are not included in this scenario."
    },
    {
      "category": "Pretest",
      "question": " A patient with chronic kidney disease presented to the ED with complaints of shortness of breath and mouth twitching after missing two dialysis sessions. The nurse noted carpopedal spasm when the BP cuff was inflated. In addition to treatment of heart failure, which of the following would the nurse expect might need to be administered? ",
      "options": {
        "A": "(A) calcium gluconate (to correct hypocalcemia)",
        "B": "(B) potassium (to correct hypokalemia)",
        "C": "(C) aluminum hydroxide (to correct hyperphosphatemia)",
        "D": "(D) magnesium hydroxide (to correct hypermagnesemia)"
      },
      "correct_answer": "(C)",
      "explanation": "(C) A patient with chronic kidney disease, who has missed dialysis treatments, is susceptible to the electrolyte imbalance of hyperphosphatemia; therefore, a phosphate-binding  drug like aluminum hydroxide (Amphojel) is indicated. Renal disease does not lead to hypocalcemia (choice (A) Or hypokalemia (choice (B). Hypermagnesemia  (choice (D) may be caused by kidney injury, but hyperreflexia (such as carpopedal  spasm) is not a sign of elevated serum magnesium."
    },
    {
      "category": "Pretest",
      "question": " A patient with a history of opioid and alcohol abuse is admitted for treatment of cellulitis. The patient has flushed, slightly moist skin and is slow to respond to verbal stimuli. The affected arm is edematous and hard to the touch, with yellow exudates noted from puncture wounds on the skin. The patient's vital signs are as follows: temperature  is 102°F (38.9°C); BP is 88/50; heart rate is 120 beats/minute; respiratory rate is 26 breaths/minute. The nurse should anticipate orders for: ",
      "options": {
        "A": "(A) antibiotic and crystalloid administration.",
        "B": "(B) antipyretic and dopamine administration.",
        "C": "(C) a CT scan of the head and a drug screen.",
        "D": "(D) colloid administration followed by norepinephrine administration."
      },
      "correct_answer": "(A)",
      "explanation": "(A) This scenario describes septic shock. The patient emergently needs antibiotics and crystalloid administration. The other 3 choices are not as effective as choice (A) is for septic shock."
    },
    {
      "category": "Pretest",
      "question": ". A patient with a history of hyperlipidemia and alcohol abuse reports left upper quadrant  abdominal pain. The patient's vital signs are as follows: temperature is 101°F (38.3C); BP is 85/50; heart rate is l10 beats/minute; respiratory rate is 24 breaths/minute. Which of the following lab values should the nurse anticipate? ",
      "options": {
        "A": "(A) decreased serum amylase level and increased WBC count",
        "B": "(B) decreased hematocrit (HCT) and increased lipase level",
        "C": "(C) decreased sedimentation rate and elevated calcium level",
        "D": "(D) increased LDH and increased SGOT (AST)"
      },
      "correct_answer": "(B)",
      "explanation": "(B) This scenario describes acute pancreatitis, which may be hemorrhagic and could cause the hematocrit to drop. Serum lipase increases with acute pancreatitis."
    },
    {
      "category": "Pretest",
      "question": " A patient is admitted with diabetic ketoacidosis (DKA), The arterial blood gas (ABG) on room air shows: pH: 7.22 PaCO: 21 mmHg pO: 94 mmHg HCO: 11 mmol/L The ABG demonstrates: ",
      "options": {
        "A": "(A) compensated metabolic alkalosis.",
        "B": "(B) compensated respiratory acidosis.",
        "C": "(C) partially compensated metabolic acidosis.",
        "D": "(D) uncompensated metabolic acidosis."
      },
      "correct_answer": "(C)",
      "explanation": "(C) The pH is low; there is an acidosis. The low bicarbonate indicates that the acidosis is metabolic. Bicarbonate drops as it is attempting to buffer the excess ketoacids. The low PaC0, is evidence that the lungs are attempting to compensate with hyperventilation,  or \"blowing off acid.\" However, compensation is only partial, not complete. (The pH would need to be normal, 7.35, for full compensation.)"
    },
    {
      "category": "Pretest",
      "question": " What is the recommended initial position to improve oxygenation for a patient with  unilateral pneumonia? ",
      "options": {
        "A": "(A) Trendelenburg position",
        "B": "(B) supine position",
        "C": "(C) side lying on affected side",
        "D": "(D) side lying on unaffected side"
      },
      "correct_answer": "(D)",
      "explanation": "(D) It is best to place the \"good\" lung down and have the patient on the side that does not have the problem. This is because more blood perfusion is greater to the \"down\" side due to gravity. If more blood goes to the \"bad\" side, hypoxemia may occur."
    },
    {
      "category": "Pretest",
      "question": " A patient is admitted with a respiratory infection. The patient has shortness of breath with a frequent productive cough and is expectorating light-green sputum. Vital signs are stable, except for the temperature, which is 39°C, and an increased respiratory rate. The nurse should anticipate which of the following ABG results? ",
      "options": {
        "A": "(A) respiratory acidosis",
        "B": "(B) respiratory alkalosis",
        "C": "(C) metabolic acidosis",
        "D": "(D) metabolic alkalosis"
      },
      "correct_answer": "(B)",
      "explanation": "(B) The increased respiratory rate generally causes hyperventilation, \"blowing off Co2,\" resulting in a decrease in the PaCO2, and a rise in the pH. Tachypnea does not guarantee hyperventilation. However, nothing in the history of this scenario indicates acidosis or metabolic alkalosis."
    },
    {
      "category": "Pretest",
      "question": " A patient has been receiving mechanical ventilation for 2 days, but the nurse notices that there is no order for nutrition. The nurse's best response would be to: ",
      "options": {
        "A": "(A) insert a feeding tube and begin enteral nutritional therapy.",
        "B": "(B) complain about the physician's practice patterns to her colleagues.",
        "C": "(C) ask the physician for an order for enteral feeding for the patient.",
        "D": "(D) assume it is the physician's responsibility for the nutritional plan of care"
      },
      "correct_answer": "(C)",
      "explanation": "(C) Early nutritional therapy for a patient who is receiving mechanical ventilation improves the patient outcome. Knowledge of evidence-based practices, however, is not enough. A critical care nurse needs to advocate for the patient using strategies that work. Collaboration (a part of the AACN Synergy Model) with the physician would be most likely to provide the patient with what he needs."
    },
    {
      "category": "Pretest",
      "question": " Which of the following critically ill patients is most at risk for development of a pressure injury? ",
      "options": {
        "A": "(A) the 66-year-old patient receiving three vasopressors",
        "B": "(B) the patient receiving mechanical ventilation",
        "C": "(C) the 81-year-old patient with an acute anterior MI",
        "D": "(D) the patient with Guillain-Barré syndrome"
      },
      "correct_answer": "(A)",
      "explanation": "(A) A patient who requires three vasopressors is experiencing profound shock with  poor perfusion to the skin, increasing the risk of a pressure injury over a shorter period of time. The remaining patients are at risk for a pressure injury, but not as great (or as rapidly) as that of the patient who requires multiple vasopressors."
    },
    {
      "category": "Pretest",
      "question": " In a patient with acute lung injury (ALD), which of the following contributes to the development of atelectasis? ",
      "options": {
        "A": "(A) loss of surfactant and interstitial fluid accumulation",
        "B": "(B) increased pulmonary vascular resistance and hypoxemia",
        "C": "(C) increased pulmonary compliance and hypoxemia",
        "D": "(D) mucosal edema and mucus plugging"
      },
      "correct_answer": "(A)",
      "explanation": "(A) The pathophysiology of acute lung injury includes damage to the Type II alveolar cells (which results in alveolar collapse) and capillary leak (which results in interstitial  fluid accumulation). Both alveolar collapse and interstitial fluid lead to atelectasis. Although mucosal edema and mucus plugging may lead to atelectasis, these problems are not associated with acute lung injury."
    },
    {
      "category": "Pretest",
      "question": " All of the following are features of an acute subarachnoid hemorrhage EXCEPT: ",
      "options": {
        "A": "(A) a sudden explosive headache.",
        "B": "(B) nuchal rigidity.",
        "C": "(C) a decreased level of consciousness",
        "D": "(D) pinpoint pupils."
      },
      "correct_answer": "(D)",
      "explanation": "(D) Pinpoint pupils are associated with pontine infarcts. The other 3 choices are fea- tures of an acute subarachnoid hemorrhage."
    },
    {
      "category": "Pretest",
      "question": " A patient is status-post inferior wall ST-elevation myocardial infarction (STEMI), with a right ventricular infarction and right ventricular failure. Which of the following data would be consistent with this patient's condition? Note that PAP = pulmonary artery pressure, PAOP = pulmonary artery occlusion pressure, and CVP = central venous pressure. ",
      "options": {
        "A": "(A) elevated PAP; elevated PAOP; elevated CVP; ST elevation in II, II, and aVF; crackles bilaterally",
        "B": "(B) elevated PAP; elevated PAOP; elevated CVP; ST elevation in V2-V6; clear lungs",
        "C": "(C) normal PAP; normal PAOP; elevated CVP; ST elevation in II, II, and aVF; clear lungs",
        "D": "(D) normal PAP; elevated PAOP; elevated CVP; ST elevation in V2-V6; crackles bilaterally"
      },
      "correct_answer": "(C)",
      "explanation": "(C) When the right ventricle (RV) fails, the pressure that is proximal to the RV (CVP) increases, whereas pressures that are distal to the RV (pulmonary artery pressure and pulmonary artery occlusion pressure) are normal or even low. This results in clear lungs. ECG changes that are indicative of an inferior wall MI are found in leads II, III, and aVF."
    },
    {
      "category": "Pretest",
      "question": " Which of the following hemodynamic profiles would best exemplify that seen in septic shock? Note that PAP = pulmonary artery pressure, PAOP = pulmonary artery occlusion pressure,  CVP= central venous pressure, and SVR= systemic vascular resistance. ",
      "options": {
        "A": "(A) PAP 20/4; PAOP 3; CVP 0; SVR 1,400",
        "B": "(B) PAP 22/6; PAOP 5; CVP 1; SVR 600",
        "C": "(C) PAP 45/22; PAOP 21; CVP8; SVR 1,800",
        "D": "(D) PAP 55/25; PAOP 15; CVP 10; SVR 1,200"
      },
      "correct_answer": "(B)",
      "explanation": "(B) The pathophysiology of septic shock includes capillary leak, which decreases intravascular volume (low CVP and relative hypovolemia), and massive vasodilatation, which decreases systemic vascular resistance (low SVR)."
    },
    {
      "category": "Pretest",
      "question": " Which of the following patients is least likely to return to a normal level of functioning after discharge? ",
      "options": {
        "A": "(A) The 70-year-old who was admitted with septic shock and is receiving chemotherapy",
        "B": "(B) The 75-year-old who was admitted for a scheduled coronary artery bypass graft procedure",
        "C": "(C) The 21-year-old trauma patient who was admitted with a pneumothorax and a fractured pelvis",
        "D": "(D) The 65-year-old who was admitted with an acute MI and a history of diabetes"
      },
      "correct_answer": "(A)",
      "explanation": "(A) The AACN believes that a critical care nurse should assess not only the patient's physiological status but also the patient's resiliency, which has been shown to affect the outcome. In addition to acute problems, extremes of age and chronic conditions also need to be considered."
    },
    {
      "category": "Pretest",
      "question": " Which of the following statements is TRUE? ",
      "options": {
        "A": "(A) Delirium is a permanent condition.",
        "B": "(B) A patient who develops delirium has an increased risk of mortality.",
        "C": "(C) Most patients with delirium are agitated.",
        "D": "(D) A patient with dementia cannot develop delirium."
      },
      "correct_answer": "(B)",
      "explanation": "(B) Studies have shown that delirium produces long-term effects. They also indicate that the more severe the delirium is, the worse is the long-term outcome. The other 3 choices are NOT true regarding delirium."
    }
  ]
}